Morning, Manicia.
早安 玛妮西娅
Big Brother, good…
哥哥 早…
Good morning.
早安
I'll bring breakfast over right away.
我现在就把早餐端过去
I'll help you…
那我来帮忙…
I can manage by myself.
我自己来就好
Master, Lady Manicia,
主人 玛妮西娅大人
I'm so sorry for being late to prepare breakfast.
抱歉 我来不及准备早餐
You've already prepared breakfast.
已经准备好了
Looks like you're still not used to getting up early.
看来你还是不擅长早起呢
That's quite the bed hair you have there.
头发都睡乱了
I'm so embarrassed by my tardiness.
各方面都这么狼狈 真是太丢脸了
Don't worry about it.
你不用这么客气啦
Living under the same roof means we should help each other.
住在同一个屋檐下 就是要互相帮助啊
But…
但是
I just can't help but feel I'm the only one receiving help.
我总觉得都是自己单方面受到帮助
That's not true.
没有这回事哦
It is.
有的
You've not only helped me lead a regular life
您不仅让我过上一般的生活
but also taught me all sorts of things.
还教会我各种各样的事
Speaking of which, both of you seem quite knowledgeable.
这么说起来 两位都很博学多闻呢
May I know who taught you all of this?
请问那些知识是谁教你们的呢
I see.
原来如此
"Apprentices"?
"门徒"吗
I told you we used to live in the slums.
我之前不是说我们住过贫民窟吗
The apprenticeship system,
所谓的门徒制度
in simple terms, is a master-apprentice relationship.
简单来说就是类似于 师父和徒弟的关系
Back then, there was this trend among nobles
当时贵族之间十分兴盛 指引贫民窟的小孩回归正途的活动
And because of that, we got the chance to study
而我们也因为这股风气
at the Knight Academy.
有幸到骑士学园学习
Knight Academy?
骑士学园？
He can't pursue his dreams because of his sister.
居然因为妹妹的关系 都不能去做自己想做的事
I feel so sorry for Rud.
路德同学太可怜了
Manicia?
玛妮西娅？
Manicia.
玛妮西娅
Yes?
怎么了
I'll be heading to the town in a bit. Is there anything you need?
我等等要去镇上 你有想买的东西吗
No… Not really.
不…不用 我没有什么想要的
I see.
这样啊
THE STRONGEST TANK'S LABYRINTH RAIDS
《最强肉盾的迷宫攻略～拥有稀少技能体力9999的肉盾，被勇者队伍辞退了》
Rud is incredible!
路德太强了
As expected of Rud.
不愧是你
You'll definitely become a knight!
你绝对可以成为骑士的
My big brother
哥哥以前
used to come out on top of every exam. He was an outstanding student.
每次测验都能夺下前几名 真的非常优秀
Everyone thought he was sure to become a knight.
所以大家都觉得哥哥 肯定会成为骑士
But…
但是
Have you heard?
欸 你听说了吗
Rumour has it that Rud
据说路德同学
has decided to become an adventurer to cure his sister's illness.
为了给妹妹治病 决定要成为冒险者哦
No way.
不会吧
But he has so much potential.
他明明这么优秀
He can't pursue his dreams because of his sister.
居然因为妹妹的关系 都不能去做自己想做的事
I feel so sorry for Rud.
路德同学太可怜了
My existence
我的存在
made it impossible for him to choose all the doors open to him.
让哥哥无法选择 其他更好更多元的未来
Come in.
请进
Are you not feeling well?
请问您身体不舒服吗
No, I'm fine. I just remembered some things.
没有 我只是想起了一些过去的事
Miss Luna?
露娜小姐？
You looked sad,
因为您看起来非常悲伤
so I thought this would help you feel better.
所以我才想借此安慰您
I'm sorry I don't have a better way of cheering you up.
不好意思 我想不出更好的安慰方法
Miss Luna, if…
露娜小姐 如果…
If someone was willing to give up their life for your sake,
有个人为了你 愿意舍弃自己的人生
what would you do?
你会怎么做呢
That person could've chosen a better path that could've made them happier.
那个人原本可以 选择一条更幸福的道路
But he gave them all up
但他却舍弃那些道路
and chose the difficult path for your sake.
选择为了你走上艰辛的路途
Even though he could've lead a happier life…
明明他可以过得更幸福的
How would you face
如果是你的话
a person like that?
会怎么面对那个人呢
Well,
这个嘛
I don't know if anyone would be willing to go that far for me,
我不知道会不会有人 愿意为自己付出到那种程度
but
但是
for that person, the path he chose is undoubtedly the one
对那个人来说这个选择
that makes him the happiest, isn't it?
肯定就是最幸福的 不是吗
The happiest for that person…
对那个人来说 最幸福…
You are talking about Master, are you not?
您说的那个人应该是主人吧
No, no…
不…不是的
Perhaps you should try to be honest with him.
不如试着跟主人好好聊一下吧
Master was willing to help an illegal Homunculus like me.
主人连我这个违法人造人 都愿意帮助了
I believe he looks at things differently than others.
我想他的想法应该和一般人不一样
But…
可是
I'm not sure how I should face him…
我不知道该用什么态度 面对哥哥才好
I tell myself I shouldn't rely on him too much,
我总是觉得不能太依赖他
so I try to keep my distance as much as possible.
所以才会尽可能地和他保持距离
But the truth is…
但是 我其实…
I really want to treat him gently.
很想温柔对待他
I'm so conflicted. I don't know what to do…
各种心情混杂在一起 让我不知道该如何是好了
Why not tell him all of your feelings, then?
那就把这些想法如实告诉他吧
"SKILL: MARKER" He… He's back!
(技能 标记) 哥…哥哥回来了
What… What do I do?
怎…怎么办
What should I tell him?
要跟他说什么才好
We cannot tell what another is thinking,
我们无法推测他人心里在想什么
so,
所以
just try expressing your thoughts to him.
试着把您的想法告诉主人吧
There.
嘿咻
I'm home, girls.
两位 我回来了
Look at all the magic greens I got…
你们看 我收到了这么多的魔菜
Big Brother,
哥哥
I have a question for you.
我有事想问哥哥
What is it?
什么事？
I'm scared.
好可怕
What… What if
万…万一
Big Brother regrets saving me?
哥哥后悔救了我 该怎么办
Are you happy with your life right now?
哥哥 你现在过得幸福吗
Of course.
当然幸福啊
How can you say that with such conviction?
为什么你可以说得这么肯定呢
Even though there are so many other paths that can make you happier…
哥哥明明还有其他更幸福的选择啊
Big… Big Brother,
哥…哥哥
why did you come back for me after I was abandoned?
你为什么要来帮助被抛弃的我呢
Because…
那是因为…
You saved me back then.
我以前曾被你帮助过啊
I… did?
我…帮助过哥哥？
Do you remember when I was a kid?
你还记得我小时候
I was often called scary because I was taller than everyone
因为长得比大家高大 长相又凶狠
and had a stern face.
所以经常被人说很可怕吧
It's Old Man Rud!
是路德大叔
He's scary! Let's get out of here!
好可怕 快逃啊
I just wanted to play with everyone…
我明明只是想跟大家一起玩啊
Big Brother!
哥哥
But you,
但是
you always stuck by my side without any fear.
你总是毫不畏惧地跟在我身边
Every time that happened, it made me really happy.
每当这时候 我都会觉得很幸福
When I decided to live with you,
决定要跟你一起生活下去时
sure, I had some doubts,
虽然也不是没有犹豫过
but I've never thought
但我从没有觉得
I made the wrong decision.
这个选择是错误的哦
Because I really love the time we spend together.
因为我很喜欢和你一起生活的时光
To me, that's when I'm the happiest.
这对我来说就是最幸福的事
I'm sorry.
对不起
I assumed how you felt.
我居然擅自揣测你的想法
I thought you weren't happy because you had to put up with me.
觉得哥哥因为我的关系过得不幸福
And because of that,
也因为我总是抱持着这种想法
I've been unsure about how to face you.
才会渐渐变得不知道 该如何面对你才好
Don't say that.
不对
I'm the one that's never been good at figuring out what others are thinking.
是我从小就不擅长察觉他人的想法
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I know.
我知道
I know you better than anyone.
因为我比任何人都了解哥哥
That's why I should be more independent.
所以我才应该更加自立自强啊
That's not true at all, Manicia.
不是这样的 玛妮西娅
Big Brother…
哥哥
Thank you, Luna.
露娜 谢谢你
But I didn't do anything.
我什么事都没做呀
If it weren't for Miss Luna,
如果没有露娜小姐
I'd have twisted myself into knots worrying over this.
我肯定会一直烦恼下去
That's why
所以
I'm really thankful to you.
真的很谢谢你
It's... It's almost time for lunch.
差…差不多该吃午餐了吧
I'll prepare the meal.
我去准备煮饭
Let's help too.
我们也一起帮忙吧
Yes, Big Brother.
好的 哥哥
Who is it?
谁啊
Who dares disturb my moment of joy with my sister?
竟敢打扰我的幸福时光
Rud, it's been a while.
路德 好久不见
Nin? Why are you here?
妮恩 你怎么会在这里
I'm here for you, of course.
还问为什么 当然是来找你的啊
They finally gave me some time off.
上头终于肯放我假了
I'm surprised Kygras let you.
真亏吉古拉斯愿意放人耶
It wasn't Kygras.
才不是吉古拉斯呢
The church gave me the break.
是教会准我休假的
I'm no longer in the hero's party.
因为我已经不在勇者小队里啦
After you left,
自从你离开后
we haven't been successful in our labyrinth raids,
我们就一直无法攻略迷宫
so the party's been disbanded.
所以勇者小队已经解散了
Everyone, battle formation!
全员进入备战状态
Lilia, what have you been doing?
莉莉亚 你从刚才开始就在搞什么
Fight seriously!
给我认真打啊
I am!
我有在认真打
Drats!
可恶
Why can't we damage it?
为什么没办法伤到它
Why are our shields wearing out so fast?
为什么我们的护盾会损耗得这么快
What's different from before?
跟之前到底差在哪里
Sir Kygras!
吉古拉斯大人
Another portal opened up.
那边的空间开始扭曲了
A new monster is coming.
又有魔物要出现了
"Life Burst"!
"生命爆发"
Activating the skill
发动技能后
cost me 1000 shield force points.
居然损耗了1000护盾值
I never knew it cost so much to use Life Burst.
原来施展生命爆发 要付出这么大的代价吗
Ever since that guy left, my skill's power has weakened.
自从那家伙不在后 感觉技能的威力也变弱了
My shield force's been depleting abnormally fast too.
护盾也耗损得异常快速
Don't tell me…
难道说…
No. That can't be.
不可能 绝对不可能
I…
我…
I am never wrong!
绝对没有搞错
I did it!
解决了
Just one more…
只要再来一次就没问题了
Um… Sir Kygras?
那…那个 吉古拉斯大人
What?
什么
Maybe the difficulty of this level is more than we can handle.
会不会是这层的难度 超出我们的负荷了呢
Forgive me for saying this,
恕我僭越
but because we aren't able to defeat all the monsters,
因为尚未完成讨伐的关系
more and more keep showing up…
魔物正在不断涌现
Shut up.
闭嘴
Nin, hurry up and heal me!
妮恩 快点帮我回复
What are you talking about?
你在说什么啊
I'm not retreating!
我绝不撤退
I can't fail again…
已经不能再失败了
"Life Burst"!
"生命爆发"
It's not working.
居然发动不了
He used up all his shield force.
护盾全部耗尽了
Kygras!
吉古拉斯
To think it hurts this much
护…护盾归零后
without the shield force…
居然这么痛
No!
不要啊
No… I don't want to die…
不…不要 我不想死
I can't die…
我还不能死啊
Get us out of here, Lily!
快离开这里 莉莉
Okay.
好的
"Dungeon Walk"!
"迷宫传送"
Curses!
可恶
Evasion-type tank? What a load of bull!
什么回避型肉盾啊
Because of you, my reputation is in tatters!
因为你们的关系 害我的评价都一落千丈了
We're sorry…
对…对不起
We're ashamed.
是我们太丢人了
That's not right.
不对吧
They did nothing wrong.
这两个孩子根本没有错
This time and the previous times,
这次和之前那几次
we failed because you charged in recklessly.
都是因为你胡乱冲锋陷阵 才会导致失败
Huh?
什么
When did you stop training?
你从什么时候开始停止训练的
You're frail now, and you've damaged your body
你现在不仅瘦弱 还因为老爱喝酒搞坏了身体
Even though you've been relying on "Life Burst" to make your way so far,
尽管你一直靠 "生命爆发"闯荡至今
do you really think that's enough to conquer all labyrinths?
但你真的以为这样就能攻略迷宫吗
It… It's worked so far, hasn't it?
之…之前不是都成功了吗
That's because we had Rud.
那是因为有路德在吧
Since Rud left,
自从路德离开后
you finally realised how your skill works, right?
你才知道自己的技能有什么特性吧
I can tell.
我看就知道了
"Life Burst" strengthens your body,
"生命爆发"虽然能强化身体
but it consumes a high amount of shield force at the same time.
但相对的也会消耗大量的护盾吧
The day Rud exhausted his shield force,
路德耗尽护盾的那天
you unleashed the most powerful "Life Burst" you've ever used.
你不是使出了至今以来 威力最强的"生命爆发"吗
After that day, I realised
那天过后我才发现
Rud's unknown skill allowed him to substitute himself
路德的未知技能能把他人损耗的 护盾转移到自己身上
So, the cost you paid for using the skill was transferred to him.
所以你之前使用技能付出的代价 都转嫁到他的身上了
After all, you used Rud's 9999 resistance skill.
毕竟你用的是路德高达9999的护盾
It's no wonder your skill became so powerful.
难怪会变得那么厉害
No, it was all me.
不对 那全都是我的实力
All I did was kick out a useless tank.
不过是踢掉一个没用的肉盾
How… How could it turn me into this?
怎…怎么可能会让我变成这样
I'm a hero!
我可是勇者耶
Enough. I've already left the party.
够了 反正我已经转出队伍了
You can continue blaming others and live an easy life.
你就继续怨天尤人 轻松过活吧
I'm leaving too. Sorry.
在下也要退出了 抱歉
I'm sorry. I might have to go train myself more.
对不起 我可能也要再去多锻炼自己
Curse you all!
可恶
I'll recover in no time and prove it to you!
我要马上把伤养好 证明给你们看
I'm the strongest!
我是最强的
I'm the hero!
我可是勇者啊
That's the story.
事情就是这样
After that, everyone left the party.
然后大家就解散了
It must've been rough for you guys.
真是辛苦你们了
I only recently figured out the effects of my skills.
我也是最近才搞清楚 自己的技能效果
I'm sorry for the trouble I caused.
是我对不起你们
You don't have to apologise.
别这么说
It's our fault for not noticing too.
没有察觉到这件事的我们也有错
Rud, I'm sorry for everything up until now.
路德 至今以来真的很抱歉
We didn't realise that you were taking on the damage for us.
我们都没发现是你 代替我们承受损伤
We were careless and let ourselves get carried away.
不小心就太大意了
I'm very sorry.
所以 真的很抱歉
Same here.
这点我也一样
If only I had figured out the effects of my skills sooner.
如果我能早点调查出 未知技能的效果就好了
So, I'm sorry too.
所以 我也很抱歉
Well, then,
那么
let's put this matter behind us now.
这件事就到此为止吧
No use dwelling on the past.
老是抓着过去不放也不是办法嘛
She's still the same as ever, always so quick to recover.
她还是老样子 振作得真快呢
You two must be Manicia and Luna.
你们是玛妮西娅和露娜吧
Hello, Miss Nin.
你好 妮恩小姐
It's nice to meet you.
请多多指教
I plan to stay here for a while.
我打算暂时停留在这里
Maybe check out the plantations. I'll be in your care.
到处逛逛看看果园之类的 请你们多多指教咯
Stay here for a while?
暂时停留？
What? You want me to leave so soon?
怎样 你希望我快点回去吗
That's not what I meant.
不是那样啦
There are no inns in this town.
这个镇上没有旅馆
We get adventurers every now and then,
即便偶尔有冒险者过来
but they have to rent vacant rooms too.
也是让他们租空房住
I see.
原来是这样啊
What should I do, then?
这下该怎么办才好
In that case,
既然如此
why not let Miss Nin stay with us?
不如让妮恩小姐住我们家吧
Can I?
可以吗
If you don't mind sharing a room with me.
如果你不介意和我挤一间房间的话
No, no, no, Manicia.
不行 玛妮西娅
I didn't mention it earlier,
虽然我刚才没提到
but Nin is the daughter of a duke. She's a genuine noble
但妮恩可是公爵家的女儿 是货真价实的贵族
and a saint.
而且还是圣女哦
Hey, don't go telling them unnecessary things.
喂 不要说那些多余的事啦
Manicia, I don't mind at all.
玛妮西娅 我不介意那些哦
If we upset the saint,
毕竟让圣女大人住得不舒服的话
we'd be on the church's hitlist.
搞不好会被教会消灭啊
Considering all that,
综合上述
you'll be staying in my room.
你就住我的房间吧
It's rather dull, isn't it?
真单调呢
But it certainly spells you.
不过 这房间很有你的风格
It's reassuring, somehow.
住着挺安心的
I'll be sleeping in the living room.
我会睡在客厅
Let's go with that for now.
那就先这样咯
Well, I wouldn't mind sleeping in the same bed as you, Rud.
如果是路德的话 我不介意和你一起睡哦
Drop the act.
你就别再演戏了
Oh, you saw through that?
咦 被发现了吗
Well,
不过
I wasn't entirely joking…
也不全然是在开玩笑哦
Rud!
路德
Rud, are you home?
路德在吗
Fil?
菲尔？
Rud!
路德
At the orchard!
果园里
A monster we've never seen before has appeared!
出现了从没看过的魔物
The orchard's completely destroyed!
果园都被摧毁了
This must be that monster's doing.
这都是那只魔物做的吧
We have to hurry up and defeat it, or else…
得赶紧打倒它才行
Sorry
抱歉 妮恩
for dragging you into this, Nin.
害你突然被卷进战斗里
Now, you're being a stranger.
你也太见外了吧
We were members in the same party, weren't we?
我们不是待过同一支小队的伙伴吗
Found it. It's that thing.
找到了 就是那家伙
Is that a wolf?
那是狼？
No. A tiger?
不 是老虎吗？
It's hard to tell with the magic element surrounding it.
因为魔素的关系 看不太清楚
Magic element?
魔素？
You mean that black miasma?
你是说那个黑色的瘴气吗
Yes. I'll purify it.
没错 我来净化它
As expected of Nin.
妮恩 你果然很厉害呢
That's nothing.
这点程度不算什么啦
This monster's biological structure
总觉得这只魔物
feels different from all the monsters I've encountered to date.
在生物构造方面 跟之前遇到的怪物不太一样
It's almost like it's being controlled by its magic element.
简直就像被魔素支配了自我似的
Are you all right?
您没事吧
Rud!
路德
Mister Vild!
维尔特先生
Father, are you all right?
爸爸 你没事吧
Leader!
队长
Sorry, I was in a haste to defeat it.
抱歉 是我太急着想打败它了
Watch out!
危险
"Taunt"!
"挑衅"
Those who can cast magic,
可以使用魔法的人
concentrate your healing spells on me!
集中对我施展回复魔法
Understood.
我知道了
Rud!
路德
Everyone,
所有人
use this chance to attack it.
趁现在攻击它
I'll take on
我会负责接下敌人的…
all the enemy's attacks!
所有攻击
Everyone has taken a lot of damage.
大家都受到了许多伤害
Luna, we're up.
露娜 要上咯
Got it.
好的
That's my Nin and Luna.
不愧是妮恩和露娜
Master!
主人
We'll keep healing you,
我会不断帮你施展回复魔法的
so go all out!
放手去做吧
Everyone, full attack!
所有人 全力攻击
I have a skill called "Sacrificial Shield"
我有个叫做"牺牲之盾"的技能
that transfers all damage taken by my allies to myself.
会把同伴受到的伤害 转移到自己身上
-With that skill... -Rud would be the strongest tank there is!
有了这个技能 路德就是最强肉盾了吧
Which means we can go all out
这样我们也能尽管攻击
without worrying about its attacks.
不必在意伤害了吧
Exactly.
没错
All right.
很好
Let's do this!
那就来大干一场吧
It's fleeing.
它逃走了
Don't let it get away!
别让它逃走了
This is bad.
糟糕
It's headed for the town.
那边是城镇的方向
A wall sprung up from the ground?
墙壁从地面上冒出来了
Luna!
露娜
Good.
很好
I'll put all the 20,000 damage I've taken so far
看我把至今承受的2万伤害
into this blow.
全都注入这一击里
"Life Conversion"!
"生命转换"
I overdid it!
做得太过头了
I might have caused more damage
比起魔物破坏的区域
than the monster…
我是不是制造出更大的损害了
Rud,
路德
thanks to you,
多亏有你
we were able to defeat the monster without any injuries.
我们才能在无人受伤的情况下 打倒魔物
You have my thanks.
真是太谢谢你了
Thank goodness.
太好了
So it's a C-rank Black Wolf?
所以它是C位阶的黑狼吗
But no matter how I think about it, it felt like it had the power of A-rank.
但我不管怎么想 都觉得它的威力应该有到A位阶
It had two magical stones?
它的身上居然有两颗魔石
That's unusual.
真奇怪呢
Monsters that can use magic typically carry magic stones,
虽说可以使用魔法的生物 身上都有魔石
but normally, it's only one.
但基本上只有一颗啊
Master, these magic stones
主人 这种魔石…
look like the ones used to create Homunculi.
看起来很像用来制作人造人的魔石
In other words,
也就是说
someone embedded magic stones
有人把人造人用的魔石 硬嵌进魔物的身体里？
Look at that.
而且你们看这里
Those are stitch marks.
似乎有缝合过的痕迹
Which means this monster was artificially created?
所以这只魔物 是被某个人创造出来的吗
Yes.
没错
This means someone tried to apply Homunculi technology to a monster.
这代表有人将人造人技术 应用在魔物身上
But
但是
isn't it illegal to create combat-type Homunculi in the first place?
制造战斗型人造人 本来就是被禁止的吧
Even if it's prohibited, there are always those curious enough to try it.
就算被禁止 还是有很多人会好奇吧
That's true.
说得也是
In the neighbouring country,
邻国好像还有个 员工全是人造人的工厂
But
但是
if they're not just interested,
如果对方不光是有兴趣
and are creating these things for some purpose…
还是为了某种意图 创造出这种东西的话…
In any case,
总而言之
let's report this to the lord.
先把这件事全部报告给领主吧
Little did we know that the appearance of this monster carrying two magic stones
此时我们还不知道 身怀两颗魔石的魔物突然出现
was merely a prelude to the events that followed.
不过是后来那个事件的前兆罢了